So let's say you have some beautiful HTML written in your
假如在 index.html 文件中
index.html file and you have some CSS set out for your HTML page.
有一些你已经写好了的 HTML 代码 和 一些页面相关的 CSS 代码
The first thing that I would want to know is,
那么首先要考虑的问题就是
how do I connect specific styling rules to
如何把对应的 CSS 样式规则
the individual HTML elements that I want to write CSS for?
应用到相应的 HTML 元素上呢 ?
That is I want to be able to write rules about
也就是说我想给某个特殊 HTML 元素
the style of specific HTML elements I've created.
指定一些特殊的样式
This is where CSS selectors come to the rescue.
这个时候就要使用到 CSS 选择器了
CSS selectors lets you identify or select specific HTML elements in a number of ways.
CSS 选择器可以让你用多种方式来选择一些特定的 HTML 元素
The three most popular are by Ids,
最流行的 3 种方式是通过 Id 属性、
by class or by type.
class 属性、元素类型
So whichever of these three that you use,
不管你使用哪一种方式
the workflow will be the same.
流程都是一样的
You'll select an element to style,
先选中你想要添加样式的元素
you'll create an object which I'll show you how to do and then you
创建一个对象 (待会儿我们会看到)
write the CSS rule for that element's property you wish to style.
然后针对你想要改变的元素属性写上对应的 CSS 样式
Let's take a quick look together.
让我们先来大致的浏览一下
So here you can see that I have a div with the class title,
这里你可以看到有一个带有 title 类名的 div、
a paragraph element with the id content,
一个 id 属性是 content 的段落标签、
and a button element.
以及一个按钮元素
Here on our web browser,
在浏览器中
you can see that they're all being rendered.
你可以看到它们都被渲染了出来
So what would happen if I added a little flair to them?
如果我们给它添加一些样式会怎样呢？
So first let's look at the type selector.
首先 来看看类型选择器（type selector）
The type selector selects specific types of HTML elements.
类型选择器用于选定某个特定的 HTML 元素类型
For example, button, notice that with types we
比如 button 类型 注意
don't prepend and either a period or the pound sign,
这里我们并没有添加额外的句号或井号
instead we just write the name of the type.
只是单纯的使用了元素类型名称
So type button and let's say I want my button to
所以我们已经选中了按钮元素
have a different color background, let say purple.
现在我们来给按钮添加一个背景颜色 比如紫色
So here is my button element,
好了 这里是我们的 button 元素、
my button type selector and here's the CSS rule.
button 类型选择器以及它对应的 CSS 规则
Let's see if it works.
让我们看看会发生什么
Now, we can see purple button,
好了 我们看见了一个紫色的按钮
but you know that buttons pretty small.
不过现在的按钮有一些小
So let's try to make it a little bigger button,
让我们把它变大一些
let's give it a height of a 150 pixels.
我们设置 150 像素的高度
Now, we're getting somewhere.
现在好了一点
It's a little hard to see the color of the text so I can change that to white
不过按钮的文字不太容易被看见 所以我们使用 color 属性
using the color property and let's add some width to it as well.
把文字颜色改为白色 同时再设置一些宽度
Now we have a button being styled.
现在我们有了一个装饰后的按钮
So in addition to type selector,
除了类型选择器之外
lets take a look at the class selector.
我们再来看看 类名选择器（class selector）
Here we have a div with the class title.
这里我们拥有一个类名为 title 的 div 元素
The selector for class uses prepended period before the name.
类名选择器通过在类名前面加一个英文句号实现
So because this is class title,
这里的类名是 title
the way that I select it as with a period followed by title.
所以我们可以通过在前面加一个英文句号来选中它
So let's make sure it's working and well say since it's our title we want
让我们来测试一下是否正确 由于它是一个标题
the font size to be really big like 54 pixels.
所以我们设置一个大点的字体 比如 54 像素
That's interesting because now we see that our P element is also going big.
不过有趣的是 我们的段落元素也跟着变大了
So let's see if we can change that using the id selector.
让我们先通过使用 id 选择器来改变它
The id selector is prepended with a pound sign like this.
id 选择器通过在 id 前面加上一个井号来选中元素
So Pound content is selecting this element with the id content.
所以井号加上 content 就选中了这个 id 为 content 的元素
We want this font size to be a little bit smaller, say 27 pixels.
我们想要字体变小一点 所以我们设置为 27 像素
Now we can see that we have set different rules
现在我们用三种不同的选择器规则
for each of our elements using the three different selector types,
选择了不同的元素
the type selector for the button,
通过类型选择器选中了按钮
the class selector for our title and the content selector for our paragraph element.
通过类名选择器选中我们的标题元素 以及使用 id 选择器选中我们的段落元素
So as I've said before,
不过就像我之前说的
it's incredibly important to debug
调试是很重要的一部分
your code which is something that just came up for me here as I'm doing this with you.
你的代码有时候也会遇见和我这里一样的情况
Maybe if you look closely you can see here that for our div with a class of title,
如果你仔细一点的话 你可以看到这个拥有 title 类名的 div
the opening tag is a div,
它拥有一个开始的 div 标签
but the closing tag is an h1.
但是结尾标签却使用了 h1
Now, that didn't cause too many problems for us because browsers are incredibly smart,
由于浏览器比较智能 所以这里并没有造成很严重的问题
but if we had kept going along it would've caused us
但是如果我忽略掉它 继续下去的话
many many problems as we develop a bigger stack of code.
它可能会导致一大堆问题 尤其在代码量比较大的时候
So right now I'm going to easily fix this by just making it a correctly closed div tag.
所以这里我们先修复它 只需要很简单的把结束标签改为 div 标签就行了
Selectors allow you a great deal of power in being able to style
选择器很强大 可以让你做很多事情
both one specific element or specific types of elements.
你可以选择某个特定元素 或者某组特定类型的元素 然后再添加样式
As you go through the lesson, you'll experience this.
在你学习这项课程时 你会慢慢体验
Now let me stop talking so that you can get to coding. Good luck.
好了 废话不多说 让我们开始写一些代码吧 祝你好运